

☑ brunocaldeira@outlook.com

Portfolio

ំ្រា Bruno Caldeira

I'm a UX/UI designer with a background in retail and telecommunication services at multinational companies. I love to create simple and creative solutions for big and complex problems.

I'm currently a user experience designer at Vodafone, leading the CRO program. Prior to Vodafone, I was an UI/UX designer at Currys PLC, where I was responsible for the user interface designs, analysis, wireframes and all UI/UX that was related to the CRO program.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## UX/UI Designer



i Mar. 2022 - Currently

- Engaged during the entire product lifecycle, using divergent and convergent thinking methods, exploring and prioritising a range of problems and solutions within a cross-functional team.
- Creating analysis for Conversion rate optimisation (CRO) purposes, including competitor analysis, user insights, analytics data, heuristic analysis and recommendations.
- Planning and analysing user research activities
- Producing concept sketches, wireframes, prototypes, interaction specs and other artefacts to support an effective user centred product development process
- Working with Product and front-end engineering, ensuring the best possible outcome from a visual and interaction design perspective
- Producing pixel perfect design layouts that are technically possible within time frames and true to the user needs
- Applying brand and style guidelines to digital products and services
- Applying usability, interaction design and research theories and principles.
- Interpreting and applying data, research, competitor analysis, heuristic analysis and insights to inform design decisions and recommendations.
- Practical knowledge of UX role in agile methodology ways of working
- Presenting objective rationale to stakeholders for design decisions

### Summary and goals:

Responsible for managing the VOXI (Vodafone's youth brand) conversion rate optimisation program, with the goal to increase sales and activations.

# UX/UI Designer



Jul. 2018 - Mar. 2022

- Creating wireframes and prototypes for user testing purposes.
- Analysing user testing and running A/B tests to validate solutions
- Creating analysis for Conversion rate optimisation (CRO) purposes, including competitor analysis, user insights, analytics data, heuristic analysis and recommendations.
- Interpreting and applying data, research, and insight to inform design decisions
- User research analysis to understand customer behaviours and journeys
- Working alongside front-end developers and Marketing teams to bring ideas and concepts to life.
- Actively working with other designers, ensuring consistency across curry's website applying brand and UI guidelines.
- Presenting and defending designs to all levels of the business.
- Creating and presenting CRO and UX workshops

#### Summary and goals:

I've created hundreds of conversion rate optimisation (a/b) tests that generated over £1m in revenue.

## Web Designer

DrinkSupermarket.com Limited

- 🗖 Oct. 2014 Jul. 2018
- Leading the product development, participating actively in brainstorms, creating sketches, wireframes, prototyping and developing pixel perfect visual layouts based on users behaviour and business requests using Adobe XD/ Photoshop as design and prototyping tools.
- Responsible for developing responsive pages based on high fidelity visuals, using HTML5, CSS3(with SASS) and jQuery, with Magento(PHP) e-commerce platform.
- Strong experience collaborating with back-end developers and Marketing team to bring ideas and concepts to life.
- Responsible for all digital visuals of DrinkSupermarket brand, such as website and affiliate banners, display animated/dynamic ads and social media artworks.
- Design and development of weekly email marketing campaigns, using photoshop, HTML/CSS and Mailchimp.

#### Summary and goals:

Redesign the whole DrinkSupermarket.com website, focusing on the user journey and experience. The process includes creating mockups, wireframes, prototypes and final visuals and then coding those visuals with HTML/CSS(SASS) on the Magento platform.

#### VOLUNTEERING

## Volunteer English Mentor

Cigloba. Projeto Globalizando

**i** Feb. 2021 - Aug. 2021

Globalizando is a non-governmental organization that aims to democratize the teaching of foreign languages in Brazil through a free, accessible, and innovative language mentoring program, based on a methodology that integrates cultural diversity and the UN Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs). With almost three semesters of existence, the organization has engaged more than 460 volunteer mentors and has already opened educational opportunities for more than 920 socio-economically disadvantaged Brazilians.

Mentors receive training on integrated content, language learning, and pedagogical facilitation. They also have the responsibilities to plan classes that are up to four students, develop activities, assist their students in internal dynamics, participate in monthly interaction and cycle assessment calls, and give at least two hours of weekly classes covering all language learning skills and exposing the participants to topics of global importance.

#### **SKILLS**

### **UX** Design

Data analysis, Research, Heuristic Evaluation, User Testing, Teamwork, Wireframing, Prototyping, User Interface Design

#### **Tools**

Figma, Sketch, Figjam, Decibel Insights, Adobe Analytics, Slack

## Languages

Portuguese and English.

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

## English - B1 GESE Grade 5 SELT

Trinity College London Issued Feb 2021  $\cdot$  No Expiration DateIssued Feb 2021  $\cdot$  No Expiration Date Credential ID TCL/010221/058505/600611532

## **EDUCATION**

### User Experience Design





# BA in Marketing and Advertising



